Hello everyone, I am Sherry from Marvelous Designer.
Next, I will show you some new features of Marvelous Designer 9.
First of all, our first new feature is GPU simulation.
In the previous version, we usually used normal simulation.
In our new version, we added a new simulation preset, which is GPU simulation.
Let's take a look at the normal simulation.
In this version, the particle diameter is relatively small.
The particle diameter is 15.
And in this version, the particle diameter is relatively large.
If we start the simulation, you will see that our simulation speed will be slower.
In the past, when we used the long-press simulation key, there were some presets here.
There are some basic simulations below.
This is our most common, most commonly used simulation attribute.
And the simulation completion is a simulation preset used to make animation.
There is also a detailed simulation.
This is a simulation preset that we will use when we need to make some very, very detailed costumes.
Now, we have added a simulation preset called GPU simulation.
GPU simulation is based on our computer graphics card.
Here, we will use GPU simulation.
When we start the GPU simulation, it needs to open a GPU simulation.
So it will be slower at the beginning of the simulation.
But we can see later that when we start the GPU simulation, even if our particle diameter is only 5,
and now we drag and drop this board, its operation speed is very fast.
This is our GPU simulation.
It will be based on a graphics card that we usually use on our computers.
So we can use GPU simulation to increase the speed.
If your graphics card attribute is better, its simulation speed will be faster.
But when we start the simulation, we will see that the GPU simulation is different from the CPU simulation.
So we suggest that when you are making costumes,
when you are making a combination costume,
or when you are making a small particle diameter costume,
use GPU simulation.
When we want to finish the final production effect,
we will switch back to the CPU simulation.
This is a simulation of the usual GPU simulation preset.
Next, I will introduce our second new feature,
which is our symmetrical editor.
This new feature is what we used to use in the past.
In the past, when we used the previous version of Marvelous Designer,
if we only had half of the board,
we would usually use the function of the vertical alignment board,
the board and the sewing line.
But now, we can directly select one of its middle lines.
On the right, we will have a function of the horizontal edit sewing line.
When we select this function,
we can see that this board will automatically open as a complete board.
And when we edit its half,
the other half will be edited simultaneously.
And if we create an internal shape in the middle,
the other side will also create a symmetrical internal shape at the same time.
When we edit the half of the board,
the other side will be edited simultaneously.
Or, when we now have a pair of symmetrical boards
and a pair of symmetrical boards,
if we create a sewing line in the middle,
we can see that the other half will also automatically create a symmetrical sewing line.
If we want to cancel the connection of this board
and make it a board that can be operated on one side,
we can find a solution in the menu on the right.
In the menu on the left,
there is a release link.
At this time, if we modify this board again,
we will see that this board can only be modified on one side,
and cannot be modified on both sides.
If you have previous project files,
our previous project files may have a set of symmetrical relationships,
but it doesn't matter.
We can directly select one of them.
We want to merge the line,
and then there is a merge in the single link.
In this way, the board after merging
is still symmetrical as the previous board.
At the same time, we can make some changes that we need.
In addition to the fact that we can make a symmetrical relationship
with the existing board,
we can also create a board that will be symmetrical itself.
Here, for example, we choose a multidirectional tool,
and then we start to create a board on the other side.
Here, click the right button,
there will be an option pop-up.
Here, there is a depth mirror tool.
If we open this function,
we can see that it will give us a horizontal line
to make a horizontal symmetry.
At the bottom, we can choose a axis.
We can make a symmetry according to the original line rate,
or we can choose x-axis or y-axis to make a symmetry.
For example, if we choose a line now,
after clicking OK, we will see that
every time we create a line,
this line will be based on the axis of our middle line
to make a symmetry.
And when we complete the creation,
the line in the middle will become
the open line we just selected.
If we modify the other half of it at this time,
the other half will also be based on this middle axis line
to make a symmetry.
In addition,
if we now choose to create
an inner polygon or a line,
we can also create
a symmetrical inner shape.
This is our second new function.
Next,
we have the third new function,
which is our penetration chart.
When we used Marvelous Designer,
we usually met many people
who needed to rebreed the grid in
Marvelous Designer.
Now we can même this type ofIES
We added two tools, one is the creation tool, and the other is the edit tool.
When we select the creation tool, if we place the mouse on a board,
we will see that the board we want to select will automatically become a white board,
and the other boards will become a gray semi-transparent state.
Then we can start to build a rebuild tool for this board.
We can choose to build a rebuild tool for the board in the 3D window,
or a rebuild tool for the board in the 2D window.
After we complete a simple layout,
we can make a detail for the grid.
We can not only manually make a detail for the grid,
but we can also directly use the edit tool.
Then the single right-click button has an all-select,
which will automatically create our selection.
Before our board is selected by us,
we can also expand the layout.
When we select a border of the layout,
we can directly expand this layout.
Then we can select a border of the layout.
Then we can directly expand this layout.
In this way, we can directly extend and crazy-slip
this layout in our design.
Then we can start to adjust
the slagged points of the slagged plane.
Otherwise, if we need to merge two slagged points,
we can select the two slagged points,
and click the right-click to merge.
Then we can merge one of these slagged point.
Of course, for example,
I can create a slagged plane again now.
Now I have two topos, and we often have to merge the middle line.
If it is not convenient to merge the two points at the same time,
we can use the editor topo tool.
In the 2D or 3D window, press the right button,
there is a function called Merge All.
When we select Merge All,
we can set the length of the upper right corner of the 3D window.
When we set a length value,
the distance between the two topos is less than the value we set,
then the two topos will merge automatically.
For example, the value we set is 3.
If we click Apply, there is no merge point.
Because the distance between the two points
is more than 3 mm.
If I set this value to 10 mm,
and then click Apply,
we can see that the middle line will merge automatically.
This is the function of Merge All.
In addition,
if we need to create a topo for this pocket,
when creating a topo in the 3D window,
we need to place the mouse on the single plate,
not on the back plate.
I recommend you to create a topo in the 2D window.
It will also create a topo according to the original plate shape.
When we create a topo,
we need to select the topo as a plate.
At this time,
we can use the editor topo tool.
In the 2D or 3D window,
click the right button.
You can see that there is an All Rebuild grid.
But here,
one is the pocket,
the other is the replacement.
The difference between these two options is that
when you select the pocket,
we will automatically convert the topo surface of the creation
into a new version.
As you can see,
I can now use the topo
as a separate version.
But when I select the bottom one,
All Rebuild grid,
and replace it,
the original version will be replaced
with the current version.
When we create the topo version,
if we open the display box on the left,
we can see that
the new version,
its grid layout,
is the grid layout of the topo we just created.
This is our third new feature,
the topo.
The fourth new feature
is the grid division.
In the process of using Values Designer,
you may encounter some of the following thoughts,
such as whether or not
you can gradually clean up some of the folds.
In our new feature,
we have added a new feature,
which is the grid division feature.
Before that,
I would like to introduce
a new tool in this version,
which is the brush selection tool.
Select the grid brush tool.
When we select this tool,
we can see that
we can directly use the brush
to select a part of the grid.
In the upper right corner,
you can see that
there is a tool bar set by the brush.
Here we can set the size of the brush.
When we modify the size of the brush,
you can see that
the size of the brush has become larger.
When we select a part of the grid,
there is a grid division button.
As you can see,
when we select this version,
its particle diameter is 20.
As you can see,
this grid is still a relatively large grid.
However, when we divide it into parts,
the number of grids in this area
will increase,
and the grid will become more delicate.
When we divide a part of the grid
into a grid,
in the right-hand attribute editor,
we can write the name of this grid.
We can also write the name of the grid
and its level.
When we set its level
to a higher level,
for example, 2,
you can see that
the grid here will become very delicate.
If we set this part of the grid
to 0,
you can see that
it returns to the original grid.
If we delete a part of the grid here,
we can delete this part of the grid
directly.
It returns to the original grid.
This may not be very intuitive.
Next, I will show you
some of the functions
in the actual use process.
First of all,
you can see that
these two versions
are exactly the same.
If I start the simulation,
you can see that
because of some of the characteristics of our grid,
its grid looks very uneven.
But now,
if we drag this version,
its movement speed is still quite fast.
The response speed is still very fast.
But if I want to make it
into a more detailed version,
I need to adjust its
particle structure.
For example, here is 20.
I need to adjust it to 10.
Then, open the simulation again.
You can see that
now our version
will become more smooth
and looks softer.
But if we drag this version,
it is very obvious
that its response speed
will not be like
the one on the right,
which is only as fast as 20 particles.
But sometimes,
we only need to
let the upper part
maintain such a fine fold.
But for the lower part,
we don't need to
make it into a very fine fold.
Because if we compare the two versions,
their differences are
more obvious
on this one.
At this point,
we can use the grid selection tool
to select the upper part of the version.
Then, we can see
that there is a grid separation
on the right side.
When we do grid separation
on this part,
and open the simulation again,
we will see that
the upper part of this version
looks a little softer.
The lower part of this version
still maintains the original shape.
When we do a grid separation
for the horizontal part,
the speed of our computer
is still very smooth.
But the horizontal part
So we can see
that the horizontal part
is still very smooth.
Of course,
if you don't want to
show the grid separation,
because the grid separation area
reminds you that
this grid is very fine.
We will change its color.
If you don't want to
show the grid separation,
in the 3D window,
there is a grid separation tool.
We can hide this tool.
So we can't see
its grid separation.
This is our fourth new function,
the grid separation tool.
OK.
Well,
that's it for
some of our
simple and latest
new functions.
But,
I have some
optimization
and some
production techniques.
The first one
is that
in our new version,
there is a new optimization,
which is 3D environment display.
I don't know
if you have
used these functions
in your daily use.
For example,
in our 3D window,
there is an environment display tool.
The first one is
our lighting controller.
When we choose to
display the lighting controller,
a lighting controller
will appear
in the 3D window.
We can adjust
the brightness
and the angle
of its lighting
by clicking
on this lighting controller.
But it is only
working in our 3D space.
In order to make it easier
for you to look at
the 3D view,
we need to
adjust the brightness
and the angle of its lighting.
Also,
there is a wind controller
next to it.
I don't know
if you have noticed
that our software
can produce wind.
If we choose
the wind controller,
there is a light
on the right.
After we turn on
the light,
we can
simulate
the effect
of blowing wind.
If we don't need
the effect of blowing wind,
just click
to close
the simulation.
That's it.
Thank you.
In addition,
we can also
adjust
whether the 3D window
shows
shadows.
Sometimes,
shadows
may affect
the effect
of our observation.
Finally,
there is
a new function.
There is
a display
grid.
Here,
we can choose
whether
it shows
the grid
in our 3D window.
In addition,
we can also
adjust
whether
the 3D window shows
shadows in
the 3D window.
We can also
adjust
whether
the 3D window
shows
shadows in
the 3D window.
We can also
adjust
whether
the 3D window
shows
shadows in
the 3D window.
In addition,
everyone may
have noticed
that there are
some tools
in our 3D window
that have been
accumulated
in two main tools.
One is
that we created
multidirectional tools.
That's all for the main content of our new project.
Here I would like to share some tips with you.
The most frequently asked question we receive is
what are the characteristics and the main reasons
for the effect of the effect when making clothes?
Next, I would like to introduce to you
some of the main reasons for the effect of the effect.
First of all, I would like to show you
what are the different effects of the effect
when we make clothes
when we have different attributes.
First of all, you can see this row of clothes at the bottom.
They are directly on the bottom window.
There is no difference between them.
On the right side, you can see
that the plants are the same.
Some of the particles are the same.
Why do we see different patterns
when we start the simulation?
The most obvious reason is that
when we start the simulation,
the first pattern is not smooth.
The second pattern is smooth
in a larger area.
The third pattern is very smooth.
The last pattern shows that
all the folds are very fine.
Where are the differences?
The reason is that
when we open the door and show the frame,
we will see that
the grid arrangement of these four patterns is different.
The first grid arrangement,
you can see that it is a triangular grid.
What are the characteristics of a triangular grid?
When you look at it,
its top is others of a triangular grid.
Its top is of a triangular grid.
It cannot be like a four-grid grid.
It is very neat.
When we simulate it,
we will see that
when we have a panel,
it is a triangular grid.
When we have a panel,
This is because we see the feeling of the upper grid of the three corners of the screen.
But in the right square grid,
the pattern is relatively smooth
when you look at the big areas below.
If we click on the display frame, we will find that it still has these unevenness problems.
Why is the third version more smooth?
It is because we used the reset grid function on this version.
When we added a new function to reset grid in MD8,
we will see that this version is very, very smooth.
The last version, why is it the most smooth and the most detailed one in the sewing box?
In fact, the properties of these four versions are exactly the same.
The small difference between the last two versions is due to the different particles.
If we look at the display frame, we can also feel that
the number of grid spaces here is significantly less than the number of grid spaces here.
When we have more grid spaces, the curve becomes smoother.
Next, let's take a look at how different these versions look when we have different particles.
In the middle row, the particles of the four versions are very different.
From left to right, the particles are 20, 10, 5 and 3.
As you can see, when your particles are 20, your simulation speed is very fast.
The left version is almost finished,
and the right version is just starting to be simulated.
We need to wait a little bit, because the version is relatively large,
and the last version has smaller particles.
As you can see, we are also simulating at the same time.
The left version is already simulated.
The right version of the particles is the third version,
and the simulation speed is very slow.
As you can clearly see,
the first version does not look very original.
Its fold is very stiff and stiff.
The second version's fold effect is already more original.
In the third version, we can see that it has more fine folds,
and its fold is very fine.
The last version is still being simulated,
so let's not waste our time.
The third version is almost finished.
The difference between the second version and the third version is not very big.
The difference is only a small difference.
Here you can see that
when the particle scale is 20,
and the particle scale is 10,
the difference is already very big.
So when you are using Amaros Designer,
it is recommended that you lower the particle scale to 10 or 5.
But if the operation speed is relatively slow,
you can use 10 for the whole version,
and then divide it into a small part.
This is the first version.
Let's look at the first version.
You can see that all the shapes are the same.
Why do these versions look a little different?
Because these versions,
first of all,
when we look at the 2D window,
it's okay.
It's just that it's a little bit weird.
In the first version,
all the shapes of the two versions are the same.
Including their physical properties,
they are also the same.
But they are very obvious.
We can see that the top version is very brittle.
Like girls,
in summer, they will wear very soft snow-covered skirts.
But the bottom version looks very hard.
The reason is because
the composition of these two versions is very different.
You may not know much about fashion.
When we make clothes,
for example,
this line and this line,
the two lines are almost the same length.
So when you look at it from the waist,
it's very flat.
But the length of the bottom version
and the top version are very different.
When we have a lot of difference,
it is easy to pile up here
into a large part of the pleats.
That is,
if you don't know the version,
you may choose to use
our rectangular version
when you make clothes directly.
There will be such a
stiff and stiff pleats.
In the first version,
we can see that
in fact,
there are some differences
between our versions.
The reason is that
in the first version,
you can see in the upper right corner,
it uses default fabrics.
In the process of using MD,
you may not pay much attention
to the fact that
our fabrics
have different physical properties.
For example,
in the first version,
it uses default fabrics.
It looks like
the bottom is flat.
There is no feeling of stretching.
But in the second version,
you can clearly feel
that it has a feeling of hammering.
Because you see,
it hammered longer below.
It is like a skirt.
It is hammered very,
very long.
The reason is that
in the second version,
it uses the default fabric.
When we click on this fabric,
there is a physical attribute preset below.
Here is a silk chiffon.
It is a default fabric.
This fabric has a feature.
When we click on it,
we will find that
its gold-plated sand strength
is very small.
In addition,
it is only 0.
The gold-plated sand strength
affects the stretching performance
of our fabric.
When its gold-plated sand strength
is very small,
this fabric
can be stretched very easily.
You may not have any idea
about how easy it is to stretch.
You can imagine that
for example,
you wear a leather top.
You wear a leather top.
Many times,
there are some leather
that are not easy to stretch.
But if you wear a sweater,
it is easy to stretch.
For example,
a sweater that is easy to stretch,
its gold-plated sand strength
is relatively small.
For example,
a leather top that is hard to stretch,
its gold-plated sand strength
is relatively large.
For example,
a silk chiffon fabric,
its gold-plated sand strength
is even only 3.
Because its purity is very, very good.
This is why
we wear dresses in summer
and use silk-plated fabric.
It will look very floating.
It is because it is very soft,
very soft.
Since our fabric strength
will affect so much,
the last two panels
are actually different.
If we look at the bottom,
there are two long ones here.
The middle one is shorter.
The one next to it
is longer in the middle
and shorter on both sides.
Why is that?
Because when you make clothes,
you may not notice it.
We have an editing text tool here.
When we choose
the editing text tool,
we will see that
the three panels at the end
have a slightly different
pattern direction.
Some panels
have a vertical pattern direction.
This is actually called
the gold-plated sand direction.
This is called the gold-plated sand direction.
It doesn't matter
if you don't know
the gold-plated sand direction.
Anyway,
as long as we see
the difference in the middle,
it is written, right?
When you use
the editing text tool,
to click this part,
you will find that
this axis
is close to the vertical one.
But if you click here,
you will find that
it is oblique.
Then you will find that
actually,
every time we click
this longer place,
it is all oblique.
Right?
Why is it oblique
and the board is longer?
Because our fabric properties
can be seen
that the angle of contact
is zero.
It means that
you can stretch
the top of your shoe
by the maximum extent.
So,
every time
we click this board,
we will find that
it is oblique.
When this axis
is oblique,
that is,
when it is in the right angle,
this board
is easy to stretch
in this part.
So,
during the process
of making,
you can check
if the direction of your fabric
is right.
Sometimes,
when the right angle of contact
is very small,
the fabric
you put on
is also oblique.
In the middle,
the skirt
may be very long.
It is not
exactly the same
as the length
of the skirt.
So,
it is not exactly
the same as the length
of the skirt.
In addition,
I would like to
show you
the folding effect
of different boards.
Mainly,
for some of our
usually made
skirts
or some
contract edges,
now,
let's look at
the bottom
of the board first.
You can see
that
we also
have
a rectangular board
of the same size.
The size
of the board
below us
is not the same
as the width.
The one on the left
is the narrowest
and the one on the right
is the widest.
At this time,
we can see
that from left to right,
our pleats
are only three
large pleats
from the beginning
to the right.
There may be
only six or seven
pleats left.
The reason is
how wide
the board
below us
is.
But
if we look at
the bottom
of the board,
the size
of the pleats
is actually
almost the same.
The width
of the board
is almost the same.
What does this
mean?
It means that
if you make
a puffy skirt
or
some
effects
you need,
if you just
sew a rectangular
board
below,
the width
may be
almost the same.
But
visually,
the pleats
are more
or less.
And we can see
that when a board
is very wide
and wide
below,
the pleats
will be
pressed
very finely.
Because we need
to press
both sides
inward,
the pleats
formed
by this board
will be
very fine
when you
look at
the pleats
formed
by the first one.
The reason is
because you put
too much fabric
here,
the pleats
will be
too thin
when you
put
too much fabric
on it.
For example,
the middle
row
you can see
that
its shape
is a little
different
from the
bottom row.
When we
start the
simulation,
we will see
that
the pleats
below
have a
clear
difference.
Where is the
difference?
The length
of the
pleats
below
is
and
the length
of the
bottom
is
600.
The length
of the
bottom
is
the same
but
the shape
is
very
different.
The reason is
that
the top
is
a fan
pleat
and
the bottom
is a
flat
pleat.
The
seam
between
the
two
pleats
is very
flat.
But the
bottom
pleat
is
rectangular
and
the
top
pleat
looks
softer
and
more
regular.
And
if we
look
at the
pleats
below,
they are
a little
smaller.
The reason is
because
the top
pleats
I will
show you
later.
When
you
sew
these
pleats
how
different
are
the
length
of
the
pleats
when
they
are
folded.
When we
start
to
simulate,
we will
see that
these
pleats
and
the
top
pleats
are
the same length.
But
we can see that
the pleats
on the left
have only
one-fourth
of the
pleats.
The
last
one
is
almost
one
and
the
last one
is
almost
one-fourth
of the
pleats.
When
you
sew
these
pleats
the top
of the
top
as
the
breasts
overlap
both
viewed
by
the
pied
和
wide
and
waist
depth
you
weight
followed
by
the
width
and
weight
of
a
When the size is small and there is a lot of volume, the panel is very large.
In addition, when we are doing such an effect,
why do we choose a spiral panel?
In fact, this panel is not a triangular panel,
it is a spiral panel.
Why is it a spiral panel?
Because a spiral panel allows us to get the largest area.
Because as we can see,
when we take a whole surface,
the fold here is the most foldable.
So when we make something,
for example, we want to add a fold of fabric to a diagonal,
we can make a spiral panel.
And we can see
that it gradually becomes narrower from a very wide panel.
Similarly, we can also see that
if we want to make some more floating bottom panels,
we need to expand this panel.
How to expand it?
There is a tool in our 2D window.
Do you know?
There is an extension tool here.
When we choose the extension tool,
for example, we now have a panel,
and then we can use the extension tool
to select the edge we want to use,
and then select a surface.
We can extend this panel.
When we extend it,
we can see that it will form a circle like the left side of us.
This makes it easy for us to keep this line above us,
and when this line is not moving above us,
we can make the amount below it as much as possible.
In this way,
when we usually make some,
for example,
when we want to make some bubble sleeves,
or when we want to make some lantern sleeves,
we can use this function.
Or when we want to make some dresses,
Then, I will introduce you to